So we know water is H2O.
لذا نعلم h2o الماء .
Each water molecule is one oxygen bonded to two hydrogens.
كل جزئ واحد الماء علاقة من ذرات الهيدروجين للاوكسجين .
And these two bonds are covalent bonds.
وهذه الروابط هي covalent الروابط .
In each of these bonds, you have a pair
في كل من هذه الروابط , لديك زوج
of electrons that are being shared
من الالكترونات التي يتم المشتركة
by both the hydrogen and the oxygen.
بكلا الهيدروجين والاكسجين .
But we also know that this isn't a completely equal sharing
ولكننا نعرف ايضا ان هذا لا مشاركة متساوون تماما
of the electrons.
من الالكترونات .
We look on the periodic table here,
نحن ننظر على دوريا هنا
oxygen is far more electronegative
هو اكثر الاوكسجين electronegative
than hydrogen is.
من الهيدروجين .
And so because of that, the electrons in these two bonds
وبسبب ذلك , الالكترونات في هذه الروابط
are going to spend more time around oxygen
سنقضي وقت اكثر حول الاوكسجين
than they are going to spend around the hydrogens.
مما س اقضي حول ذرات الهيدروجين .
And we've seen this before.
وقد راينا هذا من قبل .
This would give the oxygen end of the water molecule
هذا سنعطي الاكسجين جزيء من الماء
a partially negative charge.
جزئيا بسلبية .
That's the lowercase Greek letter delta.
هذا هو lowercase رسالة اليونانية دلتا .
We use that for the notation of partially negative.
نحن نستخدم ذلك للرمز جزئيا من سلبية .
And on the hydrogen ends of the molecule,
وعلى الهيدروجين تنتهي من الجزيئات ,
we're going to have a partially positive charge.
سيكون جزئيا ايجابية .
Now, this is the reality.
الان , هذا هو الواقع .
But as we'll see later on in future videos,
وسنري لاحقا في الفيديو , في المستقبل
it's sometimes inconvenient to have this partial messiness.
لانه في بعض الاحيان المزعجة هذا messiness الجزئية .
And so what I'm going to do right now
وما انا سنقوم به الان
is introduce you to what is fundamentally
هي اقدم لكم ما هو في الاساس
just an intellectual tool.
فقط لاداة فكرية .
It's just a convention that chemists
انها مجرد اتفاقية ان الكيميائيون
have invented that allow us to get
وقد اخترع تسمح لنا بالحصول على
our heads around a lot of reactions
رؤوسنا حول الكثير من ردود الفعل
and allow us to think about how is a reaction likely to occur.
وتسمح لنا بالتفكير حول كيف رد فعله بها .
And that intellectual tool is the idea of oxidation states.
وهذا هو اداة فكرية الفكرة من خلال عملية اكسدة المتحدة .
What the oxidation state is, even if you're
خلال عملية اكسدة ما الدولة , حتى اذا كنت
in a situation where you have covalent bond, you say,
في موقف حيث لدي covalent بوند , تقول ,
well, look, I understand.
حسنا , انظروا , انا افهم .
Those are partial charges.
تلك هي شحنات الجزئية .
These are covalent bonds.
هذه هي covalent الروابط .
The electrons are being shared.
الالكترونات يتم مشترك .
But I don't like this partial stuff.
لكن ني لا احب هذه الجزئية .
I want to just assume hypothetically,
اريد فقط ان افتراضا ,
what if these were ionic bonds?
ماذا لو كانت هذه الروابط ionic ?
And you say, well, if these had to be ionic bonds,
وتقول , حسنا , اذا كانت هذه يجب ان تكون ionic الروابط ,
then the oxygen would nab the electrons from these pairs.
ومن ثم سnab الاكسجين الالكترونات من هذه الازواج .
And so the oxygen would have a fully negative charge,
ولذلك سيكون الاوكسجين بشحن السلبية ,
a negative 2 charge.
2 سلبي .
And the hydrogens would have a fully positive charge each.
وقد ذرات الهيدروجين كل بشحن ايجابية .